the big problem is that doctors give you
anti-depressants directly when you tell
them you are sad or of have mood swings
in my case the cause was the lack of
testosterone he's male of course I found
out after the
tests this is such a big bug bear from
for me um and this is something that you
know you see and hear of all the time
guys get put on anti-depressants which
makes a rectile dysfunction worse which
creates bigger which you know can make
them more socially isolated can damage
and challenge relationship and things
and and for me like you do a set of
blood tests when you often patients will
have a set of blood test done when they
start going in with symptoms of low mood
certainly women of a certain age would
have a set of blood test done just to
check that there weren't any other
causes um and this is a real opportunity
to check these things it's not an
expensive test um but I do think that
while it's not an expensive test we tend
to test for things that we know how to
manage and actually a lot of the time
certainly in Primary Care um primary
care physicians don't tend to don't tend
and this is a broad sweeping statement
but as a general W they don't tend to
feel comfortable managing testosterone
deficiency um so I think that might be
partly where the issue is but I mean
even with people with you know um type
two diabetics we've got an absolute
opportunity there to test for
testosterone deficiency because we know
that you know 40 40% of type 2 diabetics
will develop testosterone deficiency icy
and you know start looking out for it
you know they're having regular blood
tests anyway um and yeah and it's such
an easy and really satisfying thing to
treat when you treat it early um it
keeps you know it it treats the
depression far better than an SSRI which
has limited evidence for anyway and will
as I said create even more side effects
um for that individual and won't NE
won't get people back on their feet and
back to living good happy lives nearly
as fast or if ever um as you know
normalizing someone's testosterone for
them so yeah sorry my little rant there